themiddleground.sg 2018-10-10

# Privacy Policy - The Middle Ground

The information gathered when you interact with The Middle Ground falls into two categories:

1) Personal information, which includes personal information you supply when you subscribe, order, complete a survey, register for one of our sites, enter a contest or provide your email address and

2) Non-personal information collected through technology, which includes tracking information collected by us as well as third parties.

 ** _Personal Information That You Give Us Or Ask a Third Party to Share with Us_**

 **Registration Information**

Registration for The Middle Ground may require that you supply certain personal information, including a unique email address and demographic information (Postal code, age, sex, household income, job industry and job title) to register.

Social media registration features may collect your IP address, the page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our web site.

You can disassociate your themiddleground.sg registration from third-party accounts any time.

 **User Generated Content and Public Activities (Including Comments and Reader Reviews)**

We offer you opportunities to engage in public activities on themiddleground.sg and other The Middle Ground services. “Public activities” are any actions you take on themiddleground.sg that are designed to be visible to other users, including comments, recommendations, reader reviews, ratings or any other items that you submit. Any information you disclose in your public activities, along with your screen name or IC, or any image or photo, becomes public and may be used by The Middle Ground for online and offline promotional or commercial uses in any and all media. If you choose to engage in public activities, you should be aware that any personal information you submit can be read, collected and used by other users of these areas. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in the course of your public activities and we have no responsibility to publish, take down, remove or edit any of your public activities or submissions. For more information, see the Comments FAQ and read the Forums, Discussions and User Generated Content section of the Terms of Service.

Public activities may be included in our RSS feeds, APIs and other distribution formats. As a result, your public activities may appear on other websites, blogs, or feeds. Keep in mind that we are not responsible for any personal information you choose to make public via your public activities, and you agree that such sharing will be deemed to have been done by you, not The Middle Ground. Please see our Comments FAQ for additional information.

When you share or recommend links to content on a third-party platform (such as Facebook, Google+ and Twitter), that action and any information you share will be covered by their privacy policy.

 **Reader Surveys, Reader Panels and Market Research**

The Middle Ground may collect personal information from you in connection with voluntary surveys conducted via The Middle Ground. Data may be collected through The Middle Ground, on the phone or through the mail. The information you provide may be shared, but only in the aggregate, with advertisers and partners unless we notify you otherwise at the time of collection.

Members of our Reader Panels agree to participate in surveys, polls or discussions about their readership of The Middle Ground, their household/personal characteristics and their purchase behavior.

 **Conferences and Live Events**

We often receive information about attendees to our live events from sign-in and registration lists. We may share this information with event or promotion sponsors, in which case we will notify you when we collect the information.

 _ **Non-Personal Information Collected Using Technology**_

 **Information Collected by Us Using Technology**

We use various Internet technologies to manage The Middle Ground Services and track use of the Services. Non-personal information that we collect using these technologies may be combined with other information about you.

 **Device Information**. We may collect non-personal information about the computer, mobile device or other device you use to access The Middle Ground Services, such as IP address, geolocation information, unique device identifiers, browser type, browser language and other transactional information.

 **Cookies, Beacons, Local Storage and Other Similar Technologies**. We use “cookies,” Web beacons, HTML5 local storage and other similar technologies. These technologies allow us to manage access to and use of the Services, recognize you and provide personalization, and help us understand how people use The Middle Ground. You will not be able to access certain areas of our websites, including themiddleground.sg, if your computer does not accept cookies from us. We do not respond to browser-based “do not track” signals. For more detailed information about our use of cookies and local storage, and how to manage them, see Frequently Asked Questions About Cookies and Similar Technologies in our Help section.

We may transmit non-personally identifiable website usage information to third parties in order to show you advertising for The Middle Ground when you visit other sites.

 **Analytics, Log Files and Reading History**

We have hired third parties to provide us information, reports and analysis about the usage, browsing patterns of users of The Middle Ground Services.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses (the region or general location where your computer or device is accessing the Internet), browser type, operating system and other usage information about the use of The Middle Ground Services, including a history of the pages you view.

We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, including customized Recommendations, advertising and currency display, to improve marketing, and to track access and use of The Middle Ground Services across the devices that you use to access The Middle Ground Services.

For more information on the Recommendations feature, please read the Recommendations FAQ.

We have hired third parties to provide us information, reports and analysis about the usage, browsing patterns of our users. They may independently record the type of device and operating system you are using, general location information, as well as events that occur within our apps, such as how often you use our apps.

 **Location Information**. Some of our mobile applications can deliver content based on your current location if you choose to enable that feature of the app. If you enable the location-based feature, your current location will be stored locally on your device, which will then be used by the app. If you elect to have a location-based search saved to your history, we will store that information on our servers. If you do not enable the location-based service, or if an app does not have that feature, the app will not transmit to us, and we will not collect or store, location information.

The ads in our apps are not targeted to you based on your current GPS location, but they may be targeted to you based on your postal code or device’s IP address.

 **Third Parties**

Some of the services and advertisements included in The Middle Ground Services, including on NYTimes.com and within our mobile apps, are delivered or served by third-party companies, which may collect information about your use of The Middle Ground Services.

These companies may place or recognize cookies, Web beacons or other technology to track certain non-personal information about our website users. For example, in the course of serving certain advertisements, an advertiser may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser in order to collect certain information about your use of The Middle Ground Services. For another example, an advertiser or ad server may also be able to collect your device’s unique identifier in the course of serving an ad. In many cases, this information could be used to show you ads on other websites based on your interests.

We do not have access to, nor control over, these third parties’ use of cookies or other tracking technologies or how they may be used.

Please click here to see a list of third parties that may be using cookies to serve advertising on our websites or in our apps. For example, we use Google to serve advertisements onto The Middle Ground Services, which use the Google Doubleclick cookie, and in some cases, a unique device identifier, to show you ads based on your visit to themiddleground.sg and other sites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the Google Doubleclick cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

You have choices about the collection of information by third parties on our website:

1) If you would like more about your option not to accept advertiser cookies, please click here.

2) If you would like to opt-out of having interest-based ad targeting, click here.

Your access to our websites should not be affected if you do not accept cookies served by third parties.
